The greatest lava-fueled love story ever told.
Fire of Love is a documentary film directed by Sara Dosa.
A doomed love triangle between intrepid French scientists Katia
and Maurice Krafft, and their beloved volcanoes.
Katia Conrad Krafft (voice), played by Alka Balbir.
Maurice Krafft (voice), played by Guillaume Tremblay.
Narrator (voice), played by Miranda July.
Fire of Love is a 2022 independent documentary film about the lives
and careers of volcanologists Katia and Maurice Krafft.
Directed, written, and produced by Sara Dosa, the film had its world premiere at the 2022 Sundance
Film Festival on January 20, 2022, where it won the Jonathan Oppenheim Editing Award.
It was released on July 6, 2022, by National
Geographic Documentary Films and Neon.
It received acclaim from critics, and was nominated for Best
Documentary Feature at the 95th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of married couple, volcano,
interview, volcanology, archive footage.